Guide to the Dept. of Rural Sociology records, 1920-2010.
Dept. of Rural Sociology records, 1920-2010
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Rural Sociology records, 1920-2010.
21-33-1085
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.Dept. of Rural Sociology.
4.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, office records, bulletins, reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes minutes of the New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Farm and Food Processing Labor (1948, 1950-1955); descriptions and reports concerning migrant labor in New York State and various funded projects; requests for information; and other records of Olaf F. Larson at the New York State College of Agriculture Department of Rural Sociology at Cornell University. Also, reports and bulletins (1920-1955), dept. newsletters (1961-1967), mimeographed proposals, notices, and position papers relating to challenges to governance at Cornell, collected by Harold Capener, 1965-1977 and Capener's correspondence (1963-1977).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes minutes of the New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Farm and Food Processing Labor (1948, 1950-1955); descriptions and reports concerning migrant labor in New York State and various funded projects; requests for information; and other records of Olaf F. Larson at the New York State College of Agriculture Department of Rural Sociology at Cornell University. Also, reports and bulletins (1920-1955), dept. newsletters (1961-1967), mimeographed proposals, notices, and position papers relating to challenges to governance at Cornell, collected by Harold Capener, 1965-1977 and Capener's correspondence (1963-1977).
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; Capener, Harold.; Larson, Olaf E.; Cornell University--Administration.; New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Farm and Food Processing Labor.
Subjects:
Agricultural laborers.; Food industry and trade--Employees.; Migrant agricultural laborers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Projects
Box 1 Folders 1-2
Series II. Requests for Pamphlets and/or Information
Box 1 Folders 3-8
Series III. New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Farm and Food Processing labor
Box 1 Folders 9-16
Series IV. New York State Farm Labor Program, Procedural Manual
Box 1 Folders17-30
Series V. Migrant Camps in New York
Box 1 Folders 31-46
Series VI. Other Colleges, Campus-Wide Events, Rural Sociology Faculty and Students
Box 1 Folders 47-61
Series VII. Correspondence of Harold R. Capener, 1963-1977
Boxes 1 Folders 62-69; Box 2 Folders 1-22
Series VIII. Department of Rural Sociology, Publications, Reports, Extension Reports (Bound Volumes and Various Folders)
Boxes 2 Folder 23 - Box 4
Series IX. Photographs
Box 5
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Projects
  - Rockefeller Project, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Project, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Interview of Olaf Larson by Paul Eberts, March 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series II. Requests for Pamphlets and/or Information
  - Requests for Pamphlets and/or Information Answering and Making Requests, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Answering and Making Requests, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Answering and Making Requests, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Answering and Making Requests, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Answering and Making Requests, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Answering and Making Requests, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series III. New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Farm and Food Processing labor
  - New York State Interdepartmental Committee on Farm and Food Processing Labor Newsletters, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, and Parts of Miscellaneous Drafts, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series IV. New York State Farm Labor Program, Procedural Manual
  - New York State Farm Labor Program, Procedural ManualIntroduction, TOC, Index, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Section I Administration, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Section II Year Round Help, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Section III Seasonal Help, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Section IV Employers Associations, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Section V Private Housing, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Section VI Transportation of Workers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Section VII Insurance of Workers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Section VIII Health and Medical, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Section IX Ordering and Placing Workers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Section X Labor Utilization, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Section XI Recognition, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Section XII Publicity, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Section XIII Camp Operations, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Series V. Migrant Camps in New York
  - Migrant Camps in New York Carbon Transcripts Describing Camps, Ca 1948 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Clinton, New York, Annual Reports, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Suffolk County Camp Report, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Suffolk County, Migrant Labor Committee, Minutes of Meeting, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Annual Report on Migrant Contract Systems, Summaries, Comments, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Report of New York State Migrant Child Care Program by Dr. Howard E. Thomas, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - New York State Migrants, Carbon Transcript on Camp Management, Employer-Labor Relations. Copies of MIGRATOR, 1946 (mimeo newsletter), Sample Copies of Records, etc., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Farm Labor Program, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Farm Labor Letters (mimeo letters to County Agriculture Agents from Cooperative Extension in Agriculture and Home Economics), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Farm Labor Letters and Circulars, 1946-1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - FARM LABOR PAINS (mimeo newsletter)Vol. 1, No. 1-16, May, 1944-October 1944 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Vol. 2, No. 1-17, March 1945-December 1945 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Vol. 3, No. 2-28, March 1946-December 1946 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Vol. 4, No. 1-11, February 1947-October 1947 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Home Economics Projects in Migrant Camps Case Study, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Investigation Report on Migrant Labor Camps, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Series VI. Other Colleges, Campus-Wide Events, Rural Sociology Faculty and Students
  - Other Colleges, Campus-Wide Events, Rural Sociology Faculty and Students Resolution, College of Architecture, Art and Planning, 4-22-19-- (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Proposal for Constitutional Convention (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Staff Organization Constitution, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, February 1969 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Report of Survey of Cadet Alumni of the Cornell Army, Navy and Air Force ROTC by Lillian Wilson, October 1969 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Committee of Concerned Faculty, Statement, May, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Letter to Department Heads and Chairman, College of Agriculture, April 1969 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Cornell Community of Anthropologists, Statement, April 1969 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Letter to All University Units from Committee on Mass Media, May, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "The Student as Nigger", April 1967 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Proposed Study of New York State Farm Labor System (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Surveys, Graduate Students, Committees, etc. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Position Letter, Faculty, Rural Sociology, May 6, 19-- (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Letter to Faculty, Research Proposal from Students of Rural Sociology, May, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Department of Rural Sociology, "Major Social Problems in the United States," "Social Problems Listed by Rural Sociology Faculty.", 1969? (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - "A Resolution from FCSA for Adoption by the University Faculty," "Faculty Statement" (with marginal notes), Memos Concerning Secretarial, Clerical Staff and Restructuring Committee, 1969? (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Series VII. Correspondence of Harold R. Capener, 1963-1977
  - Correspondence of Harold R. Capener, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - BA-BN, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - BO-BZ, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - C-CH, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - CI-CZ, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - D, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - E, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - F, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - G, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - HA-HD, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - HE-HZ, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - I, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - J, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - K, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - L, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mc, Mac, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - M, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - N, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - O, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - PA-PD, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - PE-PZ, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Q, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - R, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - SA-SH, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - SI-SZ, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - T, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - U, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - V, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - W, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - X, Y, Z, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series VIII. Department of Rural Sociology, Publications, Reports, Extension Reports (Bound Volumes and Various Folders)
  - Department of Rural Sociology, Publications, Reports, Extension Reports (Bound Volumes and Various Folders)
  - "The Staff and Program of the Department of Rural Sociology", 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Department of Rural Sociology Academic Staff, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Department Alumni, 1985 back to 1922, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Christmas Letter (incomplete), 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Christmas Letter, Change of Address Form, 1975, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Christmas Letter, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Holiday Letter, 1988, 1991, 1993-2005, 2007, 2009, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rural Sociology Newsletter, Vol. 1-Vol.6 (incomplete), 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rural Sociology Newsletter, Vol.1-Vol.6 (duplicates), 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Little Theatre Bulletin, 1946-1954 (Box 2)
  - "Rural Sociology in the Nineties" - CSRS Review (includes faculty vitae), 1989 (Box 2)
  - "Comprehensive Review of the Department of Rural Sociology" Sponsored by: USDA Cooperative State Research, Education and Extension Service, Cornell University Faculty Committee on Program (includes faculty vitae) Reviews, September 24-26, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Department of Rural Sociology Annual Reports of Extension Work and Special Reports, 1939-1942 (Box 3)
  - Department of Rural Sociology Annual Extension Reports 1943-45 (Box 3)
  - Department of Rural Sociology Annual Extension Reports, 1946-1949 (Box 3)
  - Department of Rural Sociology Annual Extension Reports 1950-1955 (Box 3)
  - Rural Sociology. Extension Mimeographs I - Recreation (Box 4)
  - Rural Sociology. Extension Mimeographs II -Dramatics (Box 4)
  - Rural Sociology. Extension Mimeographs III - Rural Community (Box 4)
  - Rural Sociology Extension Mimeographs IV-Music (Box 4)
  - Rural Sociology Extension Publications, 1943-1953 (Box 4)
  - Papers for Fiftieth Anniversary of Rural Sociology at Cornell, 1915-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Department Histories, 1986-2010 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of Rural Sociology and Graduate Field of Development Sociology-Publication, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series IX. Photographs
  - Department, 1932, 1947, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - New York State Extension Farm Labor Program, 1947; State Farm Labor Staff, 1944-1945; Tour of the Farm Labor Projects for Cornell, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Little Theatre, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Migrant Camp Personnel-Stout, Bullard, Floyd, Neeley,1947; Bernice Scott, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Home Demonstration Agents-Chemung County Survey, 1946; Agaton Pol and Ben Chitamber, 1958; Dr. Ernest Neal, 1958; Earl Regiman and Family, 1948; Rural Sociology Seminar Room in Mann, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Group of Graduate Students and Faculty who Organize Work Abroad- Polson, Deening, Winsor, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Staff-Barnett, Preston, Moe, no dates (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Staff-Reeder, Capener, Taietz, Eberts, no dates (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Staff-Francis, Harp, Cummings, Thomas, no dates (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Staff-Mann, Larson, Duthie, no dates (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Staff-Sanderson, Melvin, Cottrell, Anderson, no dates (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Staff-Robert Polson, no dates (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified, no dates (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Rural Sociological Society Annual Meeting, 1962 (Box Mapcase DD-12, Box 5)